DONALD HIGHE

dhighe25@gmail.com (912) 980-2870 New York, NY github.com/dhighe

ABOUT ME

I'm passionate about the creative process involved in programming and the investigative approach in testing computer software. My resilient nature allows me to handle unpredicted events well and generate alternative solutions quickly. I'm patient and collaborate well as a team member and leader. My background and diverse experience in sales, IT, and management, can be a valuable asset to a company.

SKILLS

CSS Express Node.js
HTML JQuery MongoDB
JavaScript Java Python
PLSQL AngularJS

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Computer Hardware Repair and Maintenance Sales Forecasting Customer Service

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Web Development Immersive

UNIVERSITY OF COLORADO

Bachelor of Arts and Science Major: Mathematics

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

1st Place Data Transparency Lab 2016 Hachathon

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

LINK TECHNOLOGY GROUP

Software Engineer | Valhalla, NY

04/2017 - Present

- Maintain applications for clients by correcting aspects that do not work as intended or developing new features
- Research optimal solutions and validate all alterations made on client software and servers
- Provide solution details to clients in a matter that is easy to understand
- Monitor server loads and traceback issues related to server failures to prevent further incidences

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Web Development Immersive | New York, NY 09/2016 - 12/2016

- Received hands-on with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Ruby on Rails, React, Postgres SQL and MongoDB
- Built rich, interactive, full-stack apps with key languages listed above
- Projects Include: Impossible-ish Game, Marvel Comics, YouTube Music Player

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

IBM

Helpdesk Support Agent | Boulder, CO

09/2014 - 10/2015

- Provided first level computer/software support to clients via multiple communication channels
- Diagnosed and resolved hardware/software faults
- Ensured timely response and resolution to users
- Rated #1 by customer survey for quality in customer service among IT Helpdesk team members

FIRESPOTTER LABS

Sales Specialist | San Francisco, CA

04/2013 - 11/2013

- Analyzed market trends and identified sales and business opportunities for company's up and coming teleconferencing service, UberConference
- Organized customer outreach and consistently achieved monthly sales goal
- Compiled and tracked sales data
- Assisting support team when necessary